A Guide to the Mary L. Wright Papers, 1876-1919
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Mary L. Wright Papers, 1876-1919
The Library of Virginia
52190
1.25 cu. ft (3 boxes)
Mary L. Wright
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Tim Abbott and Whiting's Old Paper.
Biographical Information
Mary H. Land (1859-1963) was born in White Marsh, Surry County to Henry Carter Land and Mary R. Marable Land (1831-1925). In 1887, Mary H. Land married Private Nicholas C. Wright (1842-1894). The Wrights co-owned and managed a general store in Surry County until Nicholas Wright's death in January 1894. In August 1894, Mary L. Wright had a son, whom she named Nicholas Carter Wright (1894-1958) after his late father. Following her husband's death, Mary L. Wright become the sole owner of the store, and managed it at least until 1900.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1876-1919, of Mary L. Wright consist of correspondence, advertisements, price lists, receipts, invoices, and contracts related to the management of the Wright's unnamed general store. Collection also includes several miscellaneous art prints and notes.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1887-1919., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 1-3)
  Correspondence, 1887-1919, is primarily comprised of letters from merchants and advertisers addressed to Mary L. Wright, in regards to the Wrights' general store. Topics include the announcement and advertisement of new merchandise, as well as from merchants seeking payment for goods bought by Mary L. Wright for her store. The majority of the correspondence comes from Virginia, though many letters originate in Baltimore, Maryland. Also included is a folder of undated and empty envelopes addressed to Mrs. N.C. Wright.
  - Correspondence, 1887-1893. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, January 1894-March 1984. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, April 1894-July 1894. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, August 1894-September 1894. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, October 1894-November 1894. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, December 1894. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, January 1895-February 1895. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, March 1895-April 1895. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, May 1895-July 1895. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, August 1895. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, September 1895-October 1895. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, November 1895-January 1896. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January 1896. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, February 1896. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, February 1896-March 1896. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1899, 1900, and 1919. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Envelopes, undated. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- General Papers, 1876-1900., Extent: 1 box. (Box 3)
  General Papers, 1876-1900, consists of the business and financial papers of the Wrights' general store. This series contains both receipts and invoices from a number of merchants and companies with whom Mary L. Wright did business, as well as advertisements of new merchandise. Also included in this series are insurance policies, as well as several art prints and miscellaneous notes.
  - Receipts and Invoices, 1885-1889. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Receipts and Invoices, 1889-1900. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Receipts and Invoices, 1900 and undated. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Insurance Policies, 1888-1889. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Advertisements, undated. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Advertisements, undated. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Papers 1876 and undated. (Box 3, Folder 11)